SRINITHI RAVICHANDRAN

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/srinithi-ravichandran-18891243/

Github: https://github.com/srinithi19 | Portfolio: https://srinithi19.github.io/react-portfolio/

Fremont - CA | Email: emailtonithi@gmail.com | Ph: (408) 412-2920

.....

OBJECTIVE

A highly motivated individual with entry-level experience specializing in Front End development, Back end Development and Full Stack Development and user interface design with an additional 6 years of work experience as Sr QA Engineer and a year of experience as a web developer. With a passion for both personal growth and for software development, I attended a certification course on Full Stack Web Development while sharpening existing skills. Ready to apply my passion for coding to a talented engineering team to develop quality solutions.

SKILLS

- Front End HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, Jquery, React JS, React Hooks, Redux
- CSS framework Bootstrap, Bulma
- Back End Python, Node.js, Express.js, REST API, GraphQL, Heroku, Unit Testing W/ JEST
- Databases: MySQL, Sequalize ORM, MongoDB
- Methodologies: OOP, MVC, Agile, RESTful Architecture, Responsive Web Design
- Version Control GitLab, GitHub
- User Interface Design Figma, Excalidraw
- OS Mac, Windows, Linux

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr QA Engineer, Commscope Inc – California, USA(July 2016 – July 2022)

- Designed, developed test plan for Ruckus ICX platform features and other protocols like VLAN,STP, RSTP, SNMP,TCP/IP and DHCP
- Developed multiple automation test libraries using python and Robot Framework for feature automation.
- Hands on experience in testing and automating RestAPI
- Actively involved in reproducing customer issues and worked with the development and support team to resolve them in a timely manner.
- Prepared deployment guide for customer and technical marketing in every release.
- Hands on experience using GIT Repository
- JIRA /Zephyr for logging defects and Confluence for our knowledge base
- Shared the knowledge with multiple teams by providing TOIs, troubleshooting documents and mentoring engineers on the assigned features.

Project Engineer, Wipro Ltd - Bangalore, India(Oct 2014 - Nov 2015)

• Design, Develop and Deploy software, provide quality assurance.

- Provide high-level customer support to remote clients using a support e-ticketing system.
- Hands-on experience in developing MVC architecture for web-based applications using Struts framework.
- Participated in code review meetings, providing input on bugs, inefficiencies and potential solutions to emergent issues.
- Delivered code to meet functional or technical specifications.

EDUCATION

· UC Berkeley Extension(Nov 2022 - Mar 2023) Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

· Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology(July 2010 - Apr 2014)

Anna University, Tamil Nadu, India.

Cumulative GPA: 9.3 / 10

PROJECTS

• Expense Tracker

Technologies: HTML, CSS bulma, JS, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MySql, Sequalize ORM, Middlewares & Handlebars and deployed using Heroku

A gamified full stack budgeting application that lets users track their income/expense and get rewards for completing challenges and quests. It is deployed on Heroku.

Repo link: https://github.com/srinithi19/Expense-Tracker

Deployed link: https://secure-anchorage-04407.herokuapp.com/

Know Your Government

Technologies: HTML5, CSS Bulma, Javascript, D3.js and involving server-side APIs

An app that lets you see how your government is organized, who can support you best, and what your government official has been doing while holding their office.

Repo link: https://github.com/bhaskell7901/know-your-government **Deployed link:** https://bhaskell7901.github.io/know-your-government/

• Support Hero

Technologies: HTML5, CSS Bulma, Javascript, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB, GraphQL, JWT, Middlewares & ReactJS and deployed using Heroku

This system allows customer support representatives to create, assign, and track customer support tickets. It provides a central location for customer support representatives to manage and prioritize customer requests. The system also enables the customer support team to respond to inquiries, track issues, and manage customer data.

Repo link: https://github.com/rmoscoe/support-hero

Deployed link: https://dry-fjord-88699.herokuapp.com/

PUBLICATIONS

• Published a paper entitled 'Matrix based key predistribution scheme for Wireless Sensor Networks' in IJCII, Vol.4: No. 2, July September 2014.